<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rahil Rehan</title>
    <link>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rahil Rehan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/software-engineering-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/software-engineering-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>What is Software Development/Engineering?  Software engineering is defined as the application of a systematic, disciplined, quantifiable approach to the development, operation, and maintenance of software. - IEEE&amp;rsquo;s Standard Glossary
Software devlopment is not just writing code, its about writing clean, understandable and maintainable code. And there are many other things involved in software development process. Things like requiremnt gathering, planning, desinging, testing, releasing and later maintaining. These aspects are also very important!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection - Spring</title>
      <link>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/dependecy-injection-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/dependecy-injection-spring/</guid>
      <description>Basics   Spring has lot of modules start.spring.io lists many spring modules which you can configure spring boot is useful to build RESTfull web services. It makes developing spring applications easy by auto configuring default components. It is opinionated framework fat jar -&amp;gt; also includes tomcat. better solution if you want to deploy on cloud platforms     Dependency Injection   Assume mail sender example, where we can have mailSender of type SMTP, POPM or MockMail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Concepts - Java</title>
      <link>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/microservices-concepts-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/microservices-concepts-java/</guid>
      <description>Microservices Concepts (Using Java technologies)  In microservices we can have multiple services running, and each service can have multiple instances as well.
Product service: browse products using rest api Order service: places order Inventory service: checks if product is available in inventory Notification service:
   Discovery Service   Each service can have multiple instances running and they need to discover each other. As we cannot particularly specify the service as they are multiple instances, referring to different service needs to be generic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Driven Development - Notes</title>
      <link>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/test-driven-development-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahilrehan.github.io/post/test-driven-development-notes/</guid>
      <description>The art of a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep is knowing you will not get woken by a support call and the piece of mind from being able to confidently change your software in an always moving market. - Nic Jackson change in code can have undesirable effect on the other parts, tests helps in making the process of changing code in future easy testing pyramid: unit testing(bottom), service/integration(middle), ui/end-end(top)  test cases should decrease as you go from bottom to top        Approach   Just write test first (use expected function) Run and fail the test Write minimal code for the test to run and fail Write minimal code to make test pass Test same function with different values Make sure all tests are passing Tests for base cases Refactor both code and tests     Features and scenarios   Given a feature, break it down to scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
